https://www.ffa.com.au/privacy

Skip to main content
Privacy Policy
1. FFA
Football Federation Australia Limited (ACN 106 478 068) of Level 22, 1 Oxford Street, Darlinghurst NSW 2010, Australia (FFA) is the governing body of the sport of football in Australia.  This Policy applies to FFA and each of its related companies and subsidiaries (referred to in this Policy as FFA, we or us).
2. About this policy
2.1  This Policy sets out the way in which FFA collects, uses and discloses personal information and also explains your rights and how to contact FFA.  FFA is committed to protecting your personal information in accordance with Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). Please read the text carefully.
2.2  We may modify or update this Policy from time to time by publishing a new version of the Policy on the FFA network of websites (including ffa.com.au, a-league.com.au, playfootball.com.au, myfootball.com.au and any related websites, mobile websites or applications which link directly to this Policy (collectively, the FFA Sites)). We will indicate any changes by updating the date of this Policy.  If you have any questions about this Policy, please contact the FFA Privacy Officer using the details in section 13.
3. Summary
3.1  FFA may collect, use, hold and disclose personal information that we collect from you or from third parties for a variety of purposes, including to provide or promote our services to you (see sections 4 – 6). You can opt-out of receiving marketing materials from FFA at any time by utilizing the unsubscribe feature on any electronic marketing communications that you receive, or in the case of other direct marketing materials by contacting the FFA Privacy Officer in accordance with section 13.1 below.
3.2  FFA may disclose your personal information to third parties in the course of our operations, including to other football organisations. From time to time, we may also provide personal information to third parties outside Australia (see sections 7 and 8).
3.3   FFA may collect information in relation to your use of our websites, including through the use of cookies. Such information may be used to optimise or maintain our website, as well as for advertising purposes (see section 9).
3.4  FFA takes reasonable steps to protect the personal information that we hold. This includes using password-protected systems to store personal information (see section 10).
3.5  You have a right to access and/or correct personal information that FFA holds about you, or to make a complaint about our handling of your personal information. You can do so by contacting the FFA Privacy Officer using the details set out at the end of this Policy (see sections 11 and 13).
4. What kinds of information do we collect?
4.1 In the course of its operations, FFA may collect, use and disclose the personal information of players, ticketholders, administrators, participants and other individuals for the purpose of governing and administering of the sport of football in Australia, as described in this Policy. The precise nature of the collection, use and disclosure of personal information by FFA depends on the services you request and receive from, and your interaction with, FFA.
4.2 Personal information collected and held by FFA may include your name, address, phone numbers, email address, date of birth, gender, occupation and social media details.
4.3  Depending on the services you receive from FFA, we may also collect and hold details about your participation history, your favourite Club and membership history as well as your emergency contact information, credit card information, driver’s license details, reference check information and details of items ordered or purchased from FFA.
4.4  In certain circumstances, FFA may collect information about your health or other sensitive information about you (for example, information about your racial or ethnic origin or physical health).  FFA may use health information about you to ensure that football programs in which you participate are run safely and in accordance with any special health needs you may have and for insurance purposes. FFA may also use health information as required by the FFA Statutes, including medical and anti-doping testing and investigations.
4.5  In addition, FFA may use de-identified health information and other sensitive information to carry out research, to prepare submissions to government or a government body or to plan events and activities.
4.6  If you choose not to provide certain personal information, FFA may not be able to communicate with, or provide services to, you. For example, you may not be able to register to play football or participate in some of the activities on the FFA Sites if you do not provide certain personal information.
5. How do we collect and hold your personal information?
5.1  We may collect your personal information from you or from a third party.
5.2  For example, FFA may collect personal information from you:
(a) via the FFA Sites;
(b) when you provide it to FFA by filling in forms approved by FFA from time to time (including when you register for an FFA Football Account);
(c) when you contact FFA;
(d) when you engage with FFA via social media;
(e) when you subscribe to receive football related newsletters or other information; or
(f) when you enter a competition that is being conducted by, or on behalf of, FFA.
5.3  FFA may also collect personal information about you from third parties, including:
(a) a Member Federation, association, club and/or a competition administrator registered with FFA from time to time (Football Administrators);
(b) your representatives;
(c) FFA corporate partners, licensees, sponsors, suppliers and broadcasters (FFA Partners);
(d) ticketing agents and event organisers, when you purchase tickets to a football related event;
(e) vendors, when you purchase football related merchandise; and
(f) the organisations identified under section 7 below.
6. For what purposes do we collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information?
6.1 FFA may collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information for various purposes, including:
(a) to verify your identity;
(b) to ensure compliance with FFA Statutes, including the administration and development of football;
(c) to organise, conduct and promote football competitions, matches, programs and other events (including for the purpose of distributing newsletters, providing information and making ticket offers);
(d) to develop programs, activities, events, products, services and merchandise relating to football;
(e) to provide you with information about our products and services, including information about tickets, merchandise and special offers, or which we reasonably believe may be of interest you;
(f) to investigate and take action in the event that applicable laws or regulations are breached, including terms of admission and codes of conduct;
(g) to carry out market research and surveys;
(h) to contact you if you win a prize in a competition you have entered and to send the prize to you;
(i) to administer, manage and improve the FFA Sites and to provide you with, or optimise your, access to those FFA Sites;
(j) so that FFA can provide you with direct marketing communications in relation to products, services, tickets, merchandise and special offers made available by FFA or our FFA Partners that we think will be of interest to you.  You will be able to opt-out of receiving direct marketing communications from FFA at any time if you so choose, by utilising the unsubscribe feature on electronic marketing communications, or in the case of other direct marketing materials by contacting the FFA Privacy Officer in accordance with section 13.1 below;
(k) where permitted by FFA, to enable FFA Partners who have a relationship with FFA to market and promote their products and services to you. You will be able to opt-out of FFA disclosing your personal information to FFA Partners for the purposes of direct marketing at any time if you so choose, by utilizing the unsubscribe feature on electronic marketing communications, or in the case of other direct marketing materials by contacting the FFA Privacy Officer in accordance with section 13.1 below; and
(l) for any use that is reasonably apparent at or around the time the information is collected or that is otherwise notified to you from time to time.
6.2 We may collect, use or disclose information about you in order to combine the information that we hold about you with information about you collected from or held by other trusted partners or from public sources. We do this in order to enable the development of consumer insights about you so that we and those other trusted companies can serve you better. This includes being able to better understand your preferences and interests, personalise your experience, enhance the products and services you receive, and to tell you about products and services. We may also use trusted service providers to undertake the process of creating these consumer insights.
7. To whom do we disclose your personal information?
7.1 We may disclose your personal information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy to:
(a) a Football Administrator that you have registered with or expressed an interest in, which may then use your personal information to administer the game of football and keep you updated with information about them.
(b) FFA’s related bodies corporate;
(c) Fédération Internationale de Football Association and its members, including the Asian Football Confederation;
(d) the Australian Sports Anti-Doping Authority, Australian Institute of Sport and/or Australian Olympic Committee;
(e) FFA’s insurers;
(f) FFA’s professional advisors, including our accountants, auditors and lawyers;
(g) third party service providers, suppliers and partners, such as ticketing agents;
(h) government agencies, regulatory bodies and law enforcement agencies, or as required, permitted or authorised by law or where we have a public duty to do so, including for purposes of safety and security; and
(i) where you have consented to your personal information being disclosed to others;
(j) anyone to whom our assets or businesses (or any part of them) are transferred; and
(k) specific third parties authorised by you to receive information held by us.
7.2 FFA Partners or Football Administrators may have separate privacy policies which apply to their collection, use and disclosure of your personal information. You should refer to that privacy policy for further details, including how you can contact the relevant FFA Partner or Football Administrator if you have any queries, or wish to make a complaint, about their handling of your personal information.
8. Do we disclose your personal information outside Australia?
8.1 FFA will store personal information on data servers that are controlled by FFA and are located within Australia where reasonably possible. However, in some circumstances, we may disclose your personal information to third parties located outside Australia, including in the USA.
8.2 In all cases, by providing your personal information to us or using our services, you consent to the disclosure of your personal information outside Australia as set out in this Policy, and acknowledge that FFA is not required to ensure that overseas recipients handle your personal information in compliance with Australian privacy law.  However, where practicable in the circumstances, FFA will take reasonable steps to ensure that overseas recipients handle personal information in a manner consistent with this Policy. You may have rights to enforce such parties' compliance with applicable data protection laws, but you may not have recourse against those parties under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) in relation to how those parties treat your personal information.
9. Using an FFA Site
9.1 If you visit an FFA Site, FFA may record information such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, the FFA Site pages accessed and any information downloaded.  This information is used for statistical, reporting and website administration and maintenance purposes, including identifying usage trends, to track users’ movements around the FFA Sites and to gather demographic information about FFA users collectively.
9.2 Like many other websites, the FFA Sites may use ‘cookies’ from time to time. A cookie is a piece of data that allows us to identify and interact more effectively with your device. The cookie helps FFA to maintain the continuity of your browsing session and remember your details and preferences when you return.  You can configure your web browser to reject cookies however some parts of our website may not have full functionality in that case.
9.3 In some cases, FFA and its third-party service providers may use cookies and other technologies such as web beacons and JavaScript on an FFA Site in connection with online services like banner advertising, website analytics and surveys to collect information about your use of an FFA Site.  The use of these technologies allows FFA and its third-party service providers to evaluate a user’s use of an FFA Site, deliver customised advertising content, measure the effectiveness of the advertising and provide other services relating to website activity and internet usage.  The services we may use from time to time include Google Analytics, Nielsen, AdTech, Omniture and Facebook.  You can find more details in the privacy policies for those services, including information on how to opt-out of certain conduct.
9.4 When we send you emails or other electronic messages, FFA may record where you open the message and click on particular links. This helps us to better understand what information is of interest to you.
10. Protecting your personal information
10.1 FFA takes the security of personal information seriously. FFA has appointed a Privacy Officer to oversee FFA's management of personal information in accordance with this Policy and the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth).
10.2 FFA uses a number of physical, administrative, personnel and technical measures to protect the security and privacy of your personal information. For example, all electronic data that is held by FFA is stored on password protected systems.
10.3 If you are considering sending us any other personal information through an FFA Site or other electronic means, please be aware that the information may be insecure in transit, particularly where no encryption is used (e.g. email).  Any transmission is therefore at your own risk.
10.4 Where FFA has given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of an FFA Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.  FFA suggests that you do not share the password with anyone and to change it regularly.
11. How can you access and correct your personal information?
11.1 FFA takes reasonable steps to ensure the personal information that FFA collects, uses and discloses is accurate, complete and up-to-date.  However, the accuracy of that information depends on the information you provide.
11.2 You have the right to access the personal information we hold about you and can request the correction of your personal data if it is inaccurate, incomplete or out of date.  If you would like to do so, please contact the FFA Privacy Officer to submit an enquiry to access the personal information FFA holds about you. The FFA Privacy Officer's contact details are set out in section  13 .
11.3 If you provided your personal information via an FFA Site, you can also update that information at any time by logging onto the relevant FFA Site and submitting the updated information.
12. Can you opt out of direct marketing communications?
You can opt out of receiving marketing messages from FFA at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions on electronic marketing communications, or in the case of other direct marketing materials, by contacting the FFA Privacy Officer in accordance with section 13.1 below.
13. Contacting the FFA Privacy Officer and Making Complaints
13.1 You may contact the FFA Privacy Officer by writing to privacy@ffa.com.au or The Privacy Officer, Football Federation Australia Limited, Level 22, 1 Oxford Street, Darlinghurst, NSW 2010.
13.2 You may complain about our collection, use or disclosure of your personal information by contacting the FFA Privacy Officer using the contact details above with your full name and contact details, together with a detailed description of the complaint. We will respond to your complaint within a reasonable period of time and inform you of the next steps we will take in dealing with your complaint. If we are unable to resolve your complaint, we will inform you of the further steps you can take.
Updated 3 October 2018
